# WENJIE (WENDY) CHEN

## FRONT END WEB DEVELOPER

Tel: (343) 988-8540 | Email: wendychen9395@gmail.com | Portfolio: https://www.hiwendychen.com/ | LinkedIn | | GitHub

## **PROFESSIONAL PROFILE**

Passionate Front-End Developer with experience in building reusable components using ReactJS & Redux and implementing UI/UX design. Master's degree recipient with a background in web design and development. Proficient in an assortment of web stacks.

## **EDUCATION**

Master of Science Systems Science, GPA 9.6/10

Jan 2018 - Oct 2020

University of Ottawa, Ottawa, Ontario, Canada

Bachelor of Engineering, GPA 4.3/5

Sep 2013 - June 2017

University of Science and Technology, Beijing, China

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## **Front-end Developer**

Dec 2020 - Present

DigLit, Toronto, ON

- Working in an agile environment with 20+ team members to deliver an application for volunteer drivers and performing peer reviewing to ensure code quality
- Developing components using Typescript and Next.js, and writing unit test to validate code performance

## **Software Developer**

Nov 2020 - Present

KataniTech Inc., Ottawa, ON

- Volunteering at a startup company for a humanitarian project to support over 2407 local businesses across
  Canada by sharing "pop-up" deals both in-store and online
- Maintaining, troubleshooting and optimizing the performance of web applications and mobile applications
- Collaborating closely with software engineer, designers and production team

## PROJECT EXPERIENCE

## Burger Builder E-commerce Application – burgershop.app | GitHub

Tech Stack: React, Redux, Material-UI, Redux-thunk, react-router, axios, Firebase

- Designed and built the web application for consumers to add or remove 4 types of ingredients and create burgers, managed the state via Redux, and stored contact information and order data in the Firebase database
- Performed user authentication on Firebase to allow customers to submit burger orders and access past orders
- Implemented responsive web design for different browser sizes including phones, tablets and computers

## A Rule-Based Expert System for Predictive Maintenance of A Hybrid Bus – master's research

Tech Stack: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, SASS, Python, Flask, flask-sqlalchemy, MySQL

- Designed a rule-based expert system with 35 rules including backend and frontend to simulate the real-time sensor data of a bus and achieved 100% correctness to predict the malfunction before it happens
- Collaborated with cloud architects and mechanical technicians to store and analyze the accurate data

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages: JavaScript ES6, TypeScript, HTML5, CSS, SQL, Python, Java

Libraries/Frameworks: React.js, Next.js, Redux, D3.js, Material-UI, SASS, Webpack, Jest, Flask, Django

RDBMS/Web Services: MySQL, SQL Server, PostgreSQL, RESTful API, JSON, AJAX, Axios

Tools/Methodologies: Git, Firebase, Microsoft Azure Environment, Agile Development, Netlify, Figma